<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BetterFencer</string>
    <string name="increase">Increase</string>
    <string name="decrease">Decrease</string>
    <string name="sets">Sets:</string>
    <string name="reps">Reps:</string>

    <string name="lat_set">lat_set</string>
    <string name="lat_rep">lat_rep</string>
    <string name="lateral_broad_jump_title">Lateral Broad Jump</string>
    <string name="lateral_broad_jump_title_short">Lateral Jump</string>
    <string name="lateral_broad_jump_guid_title">Lateral Broad Jump – Quick Guide:</string>
    <string name="lateral_broad_jump_guid_text">1. into an en garde position \n 2. Lift your front foot off the ground and hold \n 3. Using your arms to help propel you, jump as far as you can \n 4. Focus on “sticking” the landing with the back foot landing facing the same direction as when you jumped \n 5. Once you complete the full set, repeat on the opposite side</string>
    <string name="lateral_broad_jump_reps_title">Lateral Broad Jump – Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="lateral_broad_jump_reps_text">How many you choose to do in a session depends on your fencing level. If you are a beginner, start with two sets of five repetitions and gradually work your way up. If you are more advanced, you can work up to three sets of 12–15 repetitions, or more if that is not challenging enough.</string>
    <string name="lateral_broad_jump_explanation_title">Lateral Broad Jump – Full Explanation</string>
    <string name="lateral_broad_jump_explanation_text">Get into an en garde position as you normally would, then lift your front foot off the ground and hold it in the air. By simply hovering the front foot off the ground, you force your back leg to take on additional load while it performs the exercise. Using your arms to help propel you, begin your jump with the objective being to jump as far forward as you can. Your front foot should remain in the air as you land on the same back foot that you jumped off of. The back foot should land facing the same direction as you jumped (and in your en garde position). As you land, focus on “sticking” the landing and regaining your balance before completing the next rep. It can be helpful to start on a baseline and use a cone or chalk line to measure how far you go with each jump. Once you complete the full set, repeat on the opposite side to make sure you are creating balanced strength in both legs.</string>
    <string name="lateral_broad_jump_progression_title">Lateral Broad Jump – Progression</string>
    <string name="lateral_broad_jump_progression_text">There are two ways to make this exercise more challenging. The first is carry more weight while you are performing the lunge movement. For example, you can hold light dumbbells (2–5 pounds) in your hands or, as Scott prefers, wear a weighted vest. Another method is placing a source of resistance behind you, attached to your waist. This can be done with a large resistance band or bungee cord looped around your waist and then attached to a stable wall or door. Of course this can also be accomplished with a trusty friend or partner willing to hold the resistance band for you. The strength of the band and how far away you stand from it determines how challenging the exercise will be.</string>

    <string name="stan_set">stan_set</string>
    <string name="stan_rep">stan_rep</string>
    <string name="the_standing_long_jump_title">The Standing Long Jump</string>
    <string name="the_standing_long_jump_title_short">Standing Jump</string>
    <string name="the_standing_long_jump_guid_title">Standing Long Jump – Quick Guide:</string>
    <string name="the_standing_long_jump_guid_text">1. Stand with feet hip distance apart \n 2. Bend your knees and swing arms backwards \n 3. Swing arms forward and jump and land with both feet at the same time \n 4.Maintain balance and try to stick the landing </string>
    <string name="the_standing_long_jump_reps_title">Standing Long Jump – Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="the_standing_long_jump_reps_text">As with the previous exercise, if you are a beginner, you should start with only a few jumps, working your way up to the number of repetitions and sets that are challenging for you. If you are advanced, work up to at least three sets of 12–15 repetitions before you move to any progressions on the exercise.</string>
    <string name="the_standing_long_jump_explanation_title">Standing Long Jump – Full Explanation</string>
    <string name="the_standing_long_jump_explanation_text">Stand with both feet about hip distance apart. Bend your knees as you gently swing your hands backwards. Then, as you bring your hands forward again, jump forward with both feet at the same time. Your goal here is distance, and you want to get your feet out in front of you to cover as much ground as possible. Be careful not overextend to the point that you cannot maintain your balance when you land. Try to “stick” the landing and then completely reset your starting position before you proceed to the next jump.</string>
    <string name="the_standing_long_jump_progression_title">Standing Long Jump – Progression</string>
    <string name="the_standing_long_jump_progression_text">One way to make this exercise more challenging is to begin each jump with a plyometric start. Find a low, stable box or bench which allows you to stand safely above ground level (approximately 12–20 inches). Begin with your feet close to the edge, feet about hip distance apart. With a small jump, drop off the box, landing on both feet (same distance apart). Then immediately launch into your long jump. You will have to work out the proper coordination for this so that you can still use your swinging arms to propel you forward but also not resting too long before launching into the jump. You want to imagine that your legs are like a rubber band; when you first land, your muscles stretch out, and when they snap back into place, that is your long jump. If you wait too long, the plyometric effect is lost.</string>

    <string name="speed_set">speed_set</string>
    <string name="speed_rep">speed_rep</string>
    <string name="speed_skaters_title">Speed Skaters</string>
    <string name="speed_skaters_title_short">Speed Skaters</string>
    <string name="speed_skaters_guid_title">Speed Skaters – Quick Guide</string>
    <string name="speed_skaters_guid_text">1. Stand with feet hip distance apart \n 2. Lift one leg and leap in that direction \n 3. Land only on the foot that started off the ground \n 4. Alternate back and forth, ensuring that only one foot is on the ground at a time \n 5. Ensure you are moderately balanced before moving onto the next jump</string>
    <string name="speed_skaters_reps_title">Speed Skaters – Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="speed_skaters_reps_text">Beginners should start with 1–2 sets of 3–5 repetitions and focus completely on performing the elements correctly. More advanced can work up to three sets of 12–15 repetitions before adding the progressions below.</string>
    <string name="speed_skaters_explanation_title">Speed Skaters – Full Explanation</string>
    <string name="speed_skaters_explanation_text">Standing with your feet approximately hip distance apart, lift one foot so that you are standing on one leg. Using your arms to help you balance, leap in the direction of the foot that is off the ground, while continuing to face forward. You have two objectives: the first is to gain as much distance as you can. The second and more important goal is to land on the other foot (the one that started off the ground) and “stick” the landing. The exercise benefits you not only by challenging the jumping leg to propel your body through the air, but also by demanding that your other leg absorb the impact of the jump and stabilize your landing. To continue, make sure you completely regain your balance and then launch back in the direction you came from and onto the foot that you started on in the first jump. For the duration of the exercise you will leap from side to side. Each time you land, it can be helpful to let the leg that remains in the air slide out behind the standing leg (for example, the way a bowler lets his inside leg slide behind the balancing leg, only keep it in the air). Your arms play a critical role in helping you balance, and many find it helpful to allow the arm which is opposite from the landing leg, to cross in front of the body as it rotates to help absorb the lateral momentum of the jump.</string>
    <string name="speed_skaters_progression_title">Speed Skaters – Progression</string>
    <string name="speed_skaters_progression_text">This is quite a technical exercise so being able to complete a balanced landing is essential before proceeding. Once you are confident that you can, the way to progress this exercise is to make the landing a little more challenging. You can do this in several ways. The first is to complete the exercise without shoes on a forgiving surface like grass. This forces you to work a little harder to hold your balance as you land. The second way is to do the exercise on a surface that absorbs some of the impact of your landing such as a gymnastics fitness mat that is used for tumbling (because the mat compresses as you land, your muscles will have to work harder to control the weight of your body). Yet another way the exercise can be enhanced is to do it barefoot on a less stable surface, like sand. In this case, when you land, the surface actually moves slightly under your foot which means you have to really challenge yourself to stay upright (this will also build ankle strength). The good news is that if you fall, you’ve got a softer surface below you to cushion the impact. You can also try the exercise with light dumbbells in each hand, but leaping with your own body weight is preferred so you don’t compromise your technique. This is one of the exercises that shouldn’t be done in timed intervals (for Power) because doing so could compromise your ability to land the leap properly before beginning the next jump.</string>

    <string name="rev_set">rev_set</string>
    <string name="rev_rep">rev_rep</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_long_jump_title">The Reverse Long Jump</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_long_jump_title_short">Reverse Jump</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_long_jump_guid_title">Reverse Long Jump – Quick Guide</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_long_jump_guid_text">1. Start in en garde position \n 2. Raise back foot a few inches off the ground \n 3. Use your front leg to leap backwards \n 4. Land on both feet at the same time \n 5.Maintain balance and technique \n 6. Complete set and repeat on other side</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_long_reps_title">Reverse Long Jump - Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_long_reps_text">Beginners should start with one to two sets of 3–5 repetitions and focus on performing the elements correctly. More advanced fencers can work up to three sets of 12–15 repetitions.</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_long_jump_explanation_title">Reverse Long Jump – Full Explanation</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_long_jump_explanation_text">Think of this exercise as almost the opposite of the lateral broad jump, as outlined above. Get into the en garde position, and instead of lifting the front leg, hover the back leg a few inches above the ground. The toes of that front leg should be facing forward, not out to the side. Then, with as much power as you can, thrust off the front leg, launching yourself backwards as you would in a real bouting scenario. After pushing off, both feet should be in the air before landing solidly on both feet. Your goal here is distance and, like with other exercises, you want to make sure that you don’t compromise your technique. Always be sure to regain stability before beginning the next repetition.</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_long_jump_progression_title">Reverse Long Jump – Progression</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_long_jump_progression_text">To make this exercise more difficult, you can switch up the landing. But before you try the advanced progressions, first try pushing off your front foot and landing on only your back foot. Like the speed skater leaps, you should pay close attention to your balance and make sure you are completely stable before you begin another repetition. Once you have mastered this you are ready; proceed to an advanced progression which is to push off the front leg and then land only on the front leg. This will shift your balance forwards, and because you have momentum going backwards, places a lot of strain on the muscles of the front leg to control your landing (recall what we mention about eccentric motions being very important in strength training). Do not, however, modify this exercise to train Power (by adding a time limit).  Trying to perform this variation at speed will compromise your ability to maintain your balance, risk injury and diminish the value of the exercise.</string>

    <string name="pis_set">pis_set</string>
    <string name="pis_rep">pis_rep</string>
    <string name="the_pistol_squat_title">The Pistol Squat</string>
    <string name="the_pistol_squat_title_short">Pistol Squat</string>
    <string name="the_pistol_squat_guid_title">Pistol Squat – Quick Guide</string>
    <string name="the_pistol_squat_guid_text">1. Stand on one leg \n2. Slowly squat without your raised foot touching the floor \n3. Maintain control and balance throughout \n4. Start with a 45 degree bend, and work your way up to 110 degrees \n5. When you finish the set, do the same on the other leg</string>
    <string name="the_pistol_squat_reps_title">Pistol Squat – Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="the_pistol_squat_reps_text">Using the modifications above, beginners should start with 2–5 repetitions on each leg focusing completely on controlling and performing the elements correctly. More advanced levels can work up to three sets of 12–15 repetitions per leg.</string>
    <string name="the_pistol_squat_explanation_title">Pistol Squat – Full Explanation</string>
    <string name="the_pistol_squat_explanation_text">The main objective of this exercise is to go from a one-legged standing position to a squat position without losing your balance and then returning to your standing position. The deeper you squat, the more difficult the exercise; going beyond a 90 degree bend becomes very difficult. Scott recommends beginning with a 45 degree squat and then increasing incrementally to 90 degrees. Once you have mastered this comfortably, you can progress to a maximum 110 degree bend (more than this risks injury). The exercise requires a lot of mental focus and your technique is extremely important, so at first, you may need assistance. It is easy to fall if your leg muscles aren’t strong enough to fully support you throughout the full concentric and eccentric ranges of this movement. There are few ways you can modify the exercise when you are getting started. If you place a bench, (approximately knee height) behind you, you can always just sit down on that surface if you start to lose your balance. You can also use a broom stick or foam roller held vertically (like a cane) to stabilize yourself as you descend and come back up. Similarly, you can hold onto a railing or rope hanging from the ceiling which also takes a little weight off of the exercising leg. Lastly, you can ask a partner to hold one of your hands as you go up and down.\nThe exercise relies on good technique and so progressions are not advised. For those who find it difficult, building overall leg strength can help you to perform this exercise more easily. One simple way to build that strength is to use a standard leg press machine to challenge your legs to bear extra weight as you go from an extended (standing) position into a bent leg position (squat). This is, in essence, an eccentric contraction. To build on this, do one leg at a time, thus simulating the pistol squat exercise above, gradually increasing from a 45 degree to a maximum of 110 degree bend. Only use as much weight as you can handle as you slowly lower your body into the squat with focused control, then reverse and press up without bouncing.</string>
    <string name="the_pistol_squat_progression_title">Pistol Squat – No Progression</string>
    <string name="the_pistol_squat_progression_text">It’s best to focus on increased repetitions at the maximum range (110 degrees) without support.</string>

    <string name="ver_set">ver_set</string>
    <string name="ver_rep">ver_rep</string>
    <string name="the_vertical_jump_title">The Vertical Jump</string>
    <string name="the_vertical_jump_title_short">Vertical Jump</string>
    <string name="the_vertical_jump_guid_title">Vertical Jump – Quick Guide</string>
    <string name="the_vertical_jump_guid_text">1. Start in a standing position with feet slightly wider than hip distance apart \n2. Bend your knees and pull your arms behind you \n3. Swing your arms in a pendulum motion upwards as you jump \n4. The goal is to get as high as possible</string>
    <string name="the_vertical_jump_reps_title">Vertical Jump – Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="the_vertical_jump_reps_text">As this is a common movement, you can begin with as many repetitions as you feel comfortable with. More advanced fencers will want to work up to three sets of 12–15 repetitions before moving on to progressions of the exercise.</string>
    <string name="the_vertical_jump_explanation_title">Vertical Jump – Full Explanation</string>
    <string name="the_vertical_jump_explanation_text">The objective of this exercise is simple. You want to put as much distance between you and floor as possible. The starting position is with your feet a little wider than hip distance apart. Like the Standing Long Jump Exercise, bend your knees and, as you do so, swing your arms from behind you in a forward pendulum motion to give you extra momentum as you jump as high as you can. The key is to try to create as much vertical acceleration as possible which increases the amount of lift you get off the ground. For some it’s helpful to have something above you that you are reaching for, such as a hanging string or doorframe. Scott recommends using some chalk on your middle finger and, as you jump, touch a wall or doorframe to track your vertical progress. If you use this method, be especially conscious that, as you reach for your target, you don’t lose focus on your vertical lift or your landing. Many have a tendency not to jump completely vertical and when they land, one foot comes down before the other.</string>
    <string name="the_vertical_jump_progression_title">Vertical Jump – Progressions</string>
    <string name="the_vertical_jump_progression_text">A vertical jump typically relies on explosive power in both legs, however the main action we are training for (pulling distance) relies primarily on the strength of one leg (your front leg). For that reason, it can be very beneficial to also do this exercise on one leg at a time. You will find that it’s much more difficult to coordinate your balance and the height that you can reach is significantly reduced. The landing is especially important when you are jumping and landing on one leg; you will want to be careful and safeguard your foot and ankle from awkward landings. It’s important to do this exercise on both legs to balance out the strength you are building.\nIf you are able to comfortably perform three sets of 12–15 repetitions then you can progress the exercise by introducing a time limit and trying to do as many repetitions as you can within that time frame. Start with as many vertical jumps as you can do in 30 seconds using  both legs. Then work your way up to one minute. Then try this with the same time limitations using one leg at a time.</string>

    <string name="ban_set">ban_set</string>
    <string name="ban_rep">ban_rep</string>
    <string name="band_thrusts_title">Band Thrusts</string>
    <string name="band_thrusts_title_short">Band Thrusts</string>
    <string name="band_thrusts_guid_title">Band Thrust – Quick Guide</string>
    <string name="band_thrusts_guid_text">1. Attach resistance band to stable object \n2. Face away from stable object \n3. Hold on to other (knotted) end \n4. Perform simple fencing extension at normal fencing speeds \n5. Retract your arm slowly, counting to three in your head \n6. Perform on both arms</string>
    <string name="band_thrusts_reps_title">Band Thrust – Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="band_thrusts_reps_text">For beginners, start with two–three sets of 5 repetitions. Advanced fencers can work their way up to three sets of 12–15 repetitions.</string>
    <string name="band_thrusts_explanation_title">Band Thrust – Full Explanation</string>
    <string name="band_thrusts_explanation_text">Pick an extension motion that you do on regular basis. For a foil fencer this could be a thrust to the chest. For an épée fencer this could be a flicking motion to the wrist. For a sabre fencer, this could be a cut to the head. In order to add resistance, you will need to get some resistance bands. I personally like Therabands because they are light and portable. Attach one end of the band directly to something stable such as column or door handle. Don’t loop the band around the object by tying one end of the band to the other as this doubles the resistance and makes controlling the band a little trickier. Tie a knot or two at the other end of the Theraband, this is what you will hold on to. Then, standing in the en garde position and holding the band so the resistance comes from behind you, start by extending your arm back and forth in one of the extension actions you have chosen. On the extension, you want the action to be quick, so imagine counting “One” in your head. Then as you retract your arm back to the starting position, pay extra attention to controlling the movement, counting “One, Two, Three” in your head. This eccentric control is especially helpful for strengthen the stabilizing muscles in your shoulder (your rotator cuff specifically) which holds your arm in place. Make sure to do this exercise on both sides (even though you only fence with one arm) as having balanced strength on both sides is important to overall health, symmetry and injury prevention.</string>
    <string name="band_thrusts_progression_title">Theraband Thrust – Progression</string>
    <string name="band_thrusts_progression_text">To make this exercise better simulate actual fencing, it can also be performed with a handle or weapon. You can either attach the resistance band to a small handle (e.g. the last 12 inches of a broom stick) or directly on your weapon itself. If attaching it to your weapon, you will have to get a little bit creative, either tying it around the foil or épée pistol grip or the base of the saber guard. Make sure it’s secure before you begin the exercise and then practice the same movements as above with a target in front of you. This helps the action feel more realistic, thus integrating it deeper into your fencing muscle memory./nOver time, you might be tempted to add additional resistance to the exercise, however, this has a tendency to compromise your technique. For example, additional resistance can cause you to roll your shoulder slightly inwards to bear the extra weight. So rather than adding weight, it’s better to convert the exercise to train Power by adding a time limit and performing as many as possible within that period. Start with 30 seconds, then work your way up to one minute on each side. You must be especially attentive to your technique. Quality is always more important than quantity!</string>

    <string name="med_set">med_set</string>
    <string name="med_rep">med_rep</string>
    <string name="the_medicine_ball_toss_title">The Medicine Ball Toss</string>
    <string name="the_medicine_ball_toss_title_short">Ball Toss</string>
    <string name="the_medicine_ball_toss_guid_title">Medicine Ball Toss – Quick Guide</string>
    <string name="the_medicine_ball_toss_guid_text">1. Use a medicine ball you can comfortably toss up in the air and catch \n2. Find a wall, and stand a distance away equal to your height \n3. Face the wall in an en garde position \n4. Holding the ball in your back hand, twist and shove the ball towards the wall \n5. Try to hit the wall with as much force as possible \n6. Repeat on both sides</string>
    <string name="the_medicine_ball_toss_reps_title">Medicine Ball Toss – Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="the_medicine_ball_toss_reps_text">For beginners, start with two–three sets of 5 repetitions. Advanced fencers can work their way up to three sets of 15–20 repetitions, increasing the weight of the medicine ball if this becomes too easy.</string>
    <string name="the_medicine_ball_toss_explanation_title">Medicine Ball Toss – Full Explanation</string>
    <string name="the_medicine_ball_toss_explanation_text">Medicine balls come in many weights and sizes, so pick one that you can comfortably control, but also feels a little challenging to throw straight up in the air and then catch in front of you. Usually this would be in the range of 3 to 10 pounds, depending on your level. Find a sturdy wall and stand about as far from the wall as you are tall (for example, I’m 6’0” so would stand 6 feet from wall). Also, be sure to check that there are no bystanders that might be surprised by a stray toss (ouch!). Get into an en garde position facing the wall holding the ball in your back hand (e.g. your left hand if your left foot is back, or vice versa). The motion you want is a twist and shove, with your truck rotating with your arm to thrust the ball forward towards the wall. The objective of the exercise is to throw with as much acceleration as possible so that the ball strikes the wall with significant force. Then recover the ball and repeat. It is helpful to do the exercise with a partner who can collect the ball and toss it back to you, so that you don’t need to leave the starting position. The motion can feel challenging at first, but if you keep at it, your coordination will improve too. As with all one-sided exercises, be sure to do this exercise on both sides.</string>
    <string name="the_medicine_ball_toss_progression_title">Medicine Ball Toss – Progression</string>
    <string name="the_medicine_ball_toss_progression_text">You can enhance this exercise several ways: \nWhen you are very comfortable with the basic exercise, one variation is to close your eyes during the toss. This overloads the body’s system and challenges your proprioceptors (your sensory receptors focused on balance), muscles and tendons to work harder.\nYou can also place a time limitation and try to do as many throws as possible in that period (if you have a partner to help by recovering and tossing you the ball as it hits the wall). Focus on catching, twisting and releasing the ball as quickly as possible without losing any acceleration. Beginners should start with 30 seconds; advanced fencers can work up to two minutes.\nAny of the above progressions can also be done with a heavier medicine ball. However, if you feel like you are compromising the technique (e.g. you need to take an extra step to throw the ball) then you are using too much weight and should return to a lighter ball.</string>

    <string name="ben_set">ben_set</string>
    <string name="ben_rep">ben_rep</string>
    <string name="the_bench_dip_title">The Bench Dip</string>
    <string name="the_bench_dip_title_short">Bench Dip</string>
    <string name="the_bench_dip_guid_title">Bench Dip – Quick Guide</string>
    <string name="the_bench_dip_guid_text">1. Face away from stable bench \n2. Place palms on bench with fingers facing forwards \n3. Grip the front edge of the bench with your fingers \n4. Extend your feet in front of you with your legs bent at 90 degrees \n5. Bend your arms and lower your body while your feet remain in place \n6. Straighten your arms to return to starting position \n7. Do not dip past 90 degree elbow bend</string>
    <string name="the_bench_dip_toss_reps_title">Bench Dip – Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="the_bench_dip_toss_reps_text">Beginners should start with one to two sets of 3–5 repetitions with focus completely on performing the elements correctly. More advanced fencers can work up to three sets of 12–15 repetitions.</string>
    <string name="the_bench_dip_explanation_title">Bench Dip – Full Explanation</string>
    <string name="the_bench_dip_explanation_text">Find a stable ledge or bench that is approximately 18–36 inches in height. Turn your back to the ledge/bench and place your palms down with your hands facing the same direction as you are and your fingers gripping the edge. Then carefully support your body weight as you extend your feet out in front of you with your knees bent at 90 degrees. Your objective is to use your arms to lower and raise your body weight while your feet remain on the ground. Think of it as a reverse push up. Watch your form and be careful not to dip past a 90 degree elbow because it can place too much strain on the front of your shoulders.</string>
    <string name="the_bench_dip_progression_title">Bench Dip – Progression</string>
    <string name="the_bench_dip_progression_text">All you need to do to make this exercise more challenging is change the position of your feet. The first progression is to extend your legs until they are completely straight. This will increase the body weight that your arms must lower and raise. Then, to make it even more difficult, find another bench or stable object of similar (or lower) height to put in front of you and place your feet on it. By changing the angle of your legs, your arms will need to carry even more weight to complete the exercise. The final progression is to introduce an element of instability which forces your arms and core to work even harder. For this you can use a physio ball or a chair with wheels on the bottom (like you would use in an office). Place your feet up on the ball or chair and carefully complete the exercise as before. You will notice that it’s very difficult to do more than a few repetitions with both the extra weight and an unstable surface supporting your feet!</string>

    <string name="tru_set">tru_set</string>
    <string name="tru_rep">tru_rep</string>
    <string name="the_trunk_swivel_title">The Trunk Swivel</string>
    <string name="the_trunk_swivel_title_short">Trunk Swivel</string>
    <string name="the_trunk_swivel_guid_title">Trunk Swivel – Quick Guide</string>
    <string name="the_trunk_swivel_guid_text">1. Connect one end of resistance band to stable pole or column \n2. Face the column in an en garde position \n3. Hold onto the with your front arm mostly extended \n4. Move your feet backwards until there is a little resistance \n5. Pull the band to the side by rotating your trunk \n6. Hold for a moment, and return to neutral \n7. After you finish the set, repeat the exercise rotating the other direction (same arm) \n8. After you finish both of these sets, repeat with the other arm</string>
    <string name="the_trunk_swivel_reps_title">Trunk Swivel – Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="the_trunk_swivel_reps_text">Beginners should begin with light resistance and perform two sets of 5 repetitions. Advanced fencers should work towards three sets of 12–15 repetitions.</string>
    <string name="the_trunk_swivel_explanation_title">Trunk Swivel – Full Explanation</string>
    <string name="the_trunk_swivel_explanation_text">Connect one end of the resistance band of your choice (I prefer the Theraband) to a stable surface such as a pole or column. Stand facing the band and hold on to the other end with one arm. Get into en garde position with your arm mostly extended (approximately a 20 to 30 degree bend in you arm). Move backwards to stretch the band until you start to feel some resistance. Now, imagine that you have a straight line from the top of your head, through your trunk and directly to the ground. Then also imagine that your arm is fused to your trunk and cannot move from side to side. The objective of the exercise is to swivel like a top on that axis with your arm moving along with your trunk, but without changing the angle of the bend in the elbow. The more you turn, the more the band will stretch and provide greater resistance. Begin by swiveling to the outside (to the right for right-handers, to the left for left-handers). Once you hit the point where your arm is really challenged, hold briefly, then return to the starting position, slowing controlling the eccentric movement as you return to center. Once you have finished this set of  repetitions, change your foot position so that you can perform an inward turn using the same arm. To get the right amount of resistance for this opposite motion, you will need to rotate approximately 45 degrees inwards (to the left for right-handers, to the right for left-handers). Then perform the same exercise rotating inwards (left for right-handers, to the right for left-handers). Again, pause at the point of maximum rotation and then control the return to the starting position. You will feel this exercise throughout  your arm and all the way to the muscles deep inside your core and shoulder (the rotator cuff muscle). Make sure you repeat both extensions with the other arm as balanced strength is important to preventing injury and creating a complete athlete.</string>
    <string name="the_trunk_swivel_progression_title">Trunk Swivel – Progression</string>
    <string name="the_trunk_swivel_progression_text">Because this exercise is optimized when you maintain strong control over both the concentric (first part of swivel) and the eccentric motion (return to center), Scott does not advise doing this exercise with a time limit. Instead, a better progression is to increase the resistance and work to really control the motion under more challenging circumstances.</string>

    <string name="pla_set">pla_set</string>
    <string name="pla_rep">pla_rep</string>
    <string name="plank_title">Anterior Plank with Arm Extension</string>
    <string name="plank_title_short">Plank</string>
    <string name="plank_guid_title">Anterior Plank with Arm Extension – Quick Guide</string>
    <string name="plank_guid_text">1. Start in pushup position, and move arms to directly under shoulders \n2. Bend elbows 20 to 30 degrees \n3. Keep the rest of your body as straight as possible \n4. Hold</string>
    <string name="plank_reps_title">Anterior Plank with Arm Extension – Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="plank_reps_text">This is an muscular endurance exercise so beginners should start with an amount of time that they are able to complete successfully. This can be as little as 15 seconds. If you are finding it difficult to complete 15 seconds, then modify the exercise so that you are on your knees instead of your toes. Advanced fencers should work their way up to three sets of holding the position for three minutes.</string>
    <string name="plank_explanation_title">Anterior Plank with Arm Extension – Full Explanation</string>
    <string name="plank_explanation_text">Start in a typical pushup position, then reposition your hands so they are directly underneath your shoulders. Unlike the version of the exercise in the injury prevention article where you would lower to your elbows, remain on your hands. Then lower yourself slightly so that your elbows are bent at a 20 to 30 degree angle. The rest of your body should remain completely straight. The objective of the exercise is to hold this position. Make sure that you are using the muscles in your chest, core and under the shoulder girdle to stabilize your upper body. You do not want your chest to sag (causing you to crunch into the shoulders) or to arch your upper back (taking the hard work of the exercise out of your abdominal muscles and core). There should be a straight line between the top of your head and your feet and your tailbone should be tucked under.</string>
    <string name="plank_progression_title">Anterior Plank with Arm Extension – Progressions</string>
    <string name="plank_progression_text">This exercise challenges your whole body (and mind) to work to keep your body in a straight plank. If you want to make the exercise more challenging, you can do so by adding an additional element of balance. To do the first progression, spread your legs slightly, allowing for a wider base. Then lift one arm off the ground, balancing only on the other and your two feet which remain on the floor.  Make sure that you don’t shift your hips to compensate. The lifted arm can be out along side you or behind your back. Then, if you want to progress the exercise further, lift and hover the opposite foot (right foot if the left arm is in the air, or vice versa) an inch above the ground. Hold that position for 15 seconds before you return the arm and foot to the ground. Then repeat with the opposite arm and foot. Continue alternating for whatever time period you have chosen.</string>

    <string name="rev_fly_set">rev_fly_set</string>
    <string name="rev_fly_rep">rev_fly_rep</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_fly_title">The Reverse Fly</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_fly_title_short">Reverse Fly</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_fly_guid_title">Reverse Fly – Quick Guide</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_fly_guid_text">1. Use adjustable workout bench set to approximately 30 degrees \n2. Lay face down with chin over the edge of the elevated edge of the bench \n3. Grab dumbbells in each hand and slowly lift to the ceiling without bending your elbows \n4. Reach shoulder level, then slowly lower dumbbells back down</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_fly_reps_title">Reverse Fly – Sets &amp; Reps</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_fly_reps_text">Beginners should use very light dumbbells (two pounds) and try two sets of 8 repetitions. More advanced fencers can increase the weight of the dumbbells to five or even ten pounds and work towards three sets of 15–20 repetitions.</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_fly_explanation_title">Reverse Fly – The Exercise</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_fly_explanation_text">This exercise is best performed on an adjustable workout bench with a set of light dumbbells. Set the angle of the bench to about 30 degrees, then lay face down with your chin just over the edge of the elevated end of the bench. Pick up a dumbbell in each hand and use your toes to stabilize yourself on the ground. Without bending your arms, slowly lift the backs of your hands towards the ceiling. When your hands reach the level of your shoulders, slowly lower your arms back to the starting position.</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_fly_progression_title">Reverse Fly – Progressions</string>
    <string name="the_reverse_fly_progression_text">There are two ways to progress this exercise. The first is to introduce a brief pause (this is called “isometrics”) to increase the strain on the muscles. While you are performing a repetition, pick a point (usually this is when the weights are at the highest point off the ground) to simply hold the dumbbell in place for 5–10 seconds. Then resume the repetition. You can introduce this element sporadically into your sets, including more and more until you are performing this movement in every rep. Another way to progress the exercise is to add a time limit and do as many as you can in that period (e.g. five pound weights for 30 seconds). Work your way up to one minute if you can!  If you choose this progression, you would not want to use the isometric progression described above since your objective is to do as many reps as possible within your time frame.</string>

</resources>
